3,891 gigawatts in 2025, representing an increase of 185% for the past 15 years.
Growth trend detailed analysis can be divided into two stages.
2011 to 2020 is steady growth phase.
During this decade, annual new installed capacity is about 120 GW.
This phase leads a solid foundation for subsequent high-speed development.
2021 to 2025 is high-speed growth phase.
The growth of total installed capacity accelerated markedly.
annual capacity exceeded 250 GW, reaching 3,891 GW by the end of 2025.
The average annual blue screen for the past 15 years is nearly 10%.
This diagram shows the power capacity distribution in China.
Over the past 10 years, China's power installation mix has undergone a historic shift from fossil energy dominance to clean energy dominance.
The share of thermal power installed capacity has dropped substantially, while non-fossil energy, particularly wind and solar power, has achieved explosive growth
and become the core energy driving the green transition of energy structure.
You can get two conclusions from this diagram.
The first, the share of thermal power continuously decline.
Here I said the thermal power means coal power because in China the thermal power meaning is coal power.
You can see for the coal power fell from 67.3% in 2014 to 39.6% in 2045.
So these marks are notable reduction in the power system to reliance on the coal.
The second stage, the second point is no fossil energy becomes the mainstay.
The share of installed non-photo energy capacity, including hydropower, solar power, wind power, and nuclear power,
rose steadily from 32.7% in 2014 to 40.4% in 2025, taking an outright leading position for the first time.
And this diagram shows the proportion of power generation in China in 2024.
And in that slide we know that coal power accounted for 43% of the total installed capacity,
lower than 48% of new energy.
However, from this figure we can find the coal power contributed about 63% of the total power generation.
1.8 times that of new energy power.
Which means in 2024, the installed capacity for coal power is only 43%, but the power generation is about 63%.
Which means although wind and solar power have registered rapid growth, their utilization rates remain relatively low.
Hence, coal power remains the final safeguard for the secure operation of the power grid in China.
From the above data, we can get the conclusion that coal power state plays a very important role in China.
Therefore, this report focuses on the development and application of clean coal power technology.
The development of clinical power technology has gone through three stages in China.
The 1970s to 1990s is the initial stage.
This stage talks on post-combustion fuel gas desulfurization and dust removal technology
to address acid, rain and dust pollution,
leading the foundation for environmental governance.
You can find in this period for nitrogen octane or NOx, there is no limitation.
There is only limitation standard for salts, sulfur oxides and dust.
There is no limitation for NOx.
The second stage is 2010.
2000 to 2010, it is a development stage.
This stage shifted towards improving power generation efficiency technologies, such as
super-critical power generation technology, and multi-protein control technologies, such
as neutral low-emission technology.
The third stage is 2020 to present.
This stage is a deepening transformation stage.
It focuses on synergistic reduction of pollutants and carbon,
developing higher efficiency technologies,
flexibility in electricity,
and integration with CCUS for low-carbon transition.
I use three sentences to summarize the China code's core position in China.
The first sentence is the best stone for energy security.
China has built the world's largest clean coal power system, contributing 60% of power generation and 80% of peak shipping capacity.
It serves as the best stone for energy security and the stabilizer of energy.
Second sentence is a green benchmark for fossil power.
By the end of 2025, over 95% of coal-fired power units in China had achieved neutral
emissions, reaching an international eating clean level.
The third is the power engine for low-carbon upgrades.
The average power supply co-consumption dropped to 301.6 grams per kilowatt in 2014,
with thermal efficiency exceeding 50% for the world's first 630 Celsius degree UTC unit.
or USC unit.
Chinese government has released some key documents
to provide policy guidance for clean coal power.
In this April, Chinese government
ensued opinions on energy conservation and carbon
reduction.
This document emphasizes strengthening energy ceiling,
carbon-reducing, and flexibility retrofitting of coal power, focusing on
performance improvement of existing units. The second document is the 15th five-year plan
for modern energy system. It requires promoting clean and efficient utilization
utilization of coal, and ordering reduction and substitution, setting a target of reducing
the average power supply coal consumption to below 300 grams per kilowatt by 2025.
The third document is Action Plan for Carbon Peaking Before 2030, and this one is related
to the Chinese double carbon codes, the dual carbon codes.
I will talk about the dual carbon codes in a moment.
This power requires strictly controlling new coal power projects
and promoting the triple retrofit energy saving, combined heat and power, or CHP.
flexibility benefit of existing units.
After the overview of the history, status, and supporting forces of China's clinical sector,
now we will move on to Chapter 2.
We will detail the key clinical power technologies.
Co-processing stages for clinical utilization include pre-, in-, and after-combustion treatment
processes.
Pre-combustion or before combustion, co-quality is improved from the source through co-washing
and co-blending technology.
For cold washing technology, it can reduce ash and sulfur through washing processes.
China's low cold washing rate has reached 78.6% in 2020.
On cold bladding technology, it can significantly enhance different cold types for stable, efficient, and low-potion combustion.
In combustion, or during combustion, low nitrogen combustion technology is used to inhibit pollutant
formation.
Its principle is to inhibit nitrogen oxide, or NOx, formation through air staging, fuel
stage and low gas refrigeration and its effect can reduce NOx concentration at
boiler outlet to 200 to 300 milligram per meter cube. Reducing the burden on subsequent SCR system post
post-combustion or after-combustion.
Through a major combination of flue gas
purification technologies, including
SCR denitrification, wet desilverization,
and high-efficiency dust removal,
neutral emissions of pollutants are achieved.
These figures show pre-combustion
technologies, including coal washing, coal plating, coal brackets, and coal water storing.
Its core principle is to remove ash and silver by physical and chemical coal washing to improve
coal quality, and mix different kinds of coal scientifically by coal plating to increase
increase combustion efficiency, which has the advantages of improved efficiency.
It can stabilize coal quality, increase boiler combustion efficiency greatly,
reduce combustion fluctuations and clean emissions.
It can remove ash and sulfur from coal salts,
greatly reduce dust and salt emissions,
and reduce costs, it can blend low price coal, optimize fuel structure, reduce fuel costs effectively.
During combustion, low NOx combustion technology constitutes the first line of defense for NOx emission control.
control. By adopting L-staging and fuel staging methods, combined with advanced low NOx burners,
it can effectively inhibit NOx formation with an efficiency of more than 50%.
For the in-combustion, there are several practical methods. First is L-stage combustion.
Air-stage combustion is the staged supply of combustion air into the furnace,
creates a fuel-rich, low-oxygen-reducing atmosphere in primary combustion zone,
inhibiting the formation of thermal knots at the source.
And the second is fuel-stage combustion method.
The secondary field, or regrounding field, is injected downstream of primary combustion
zone to form a strong reducing zone, which reduces the generated knots into harmless
nitrogen.
The third is flue gas recirculation, or FGR.
Extracted low temperature flue gas is mixed with combustion air to reduce oxygen concentration
and flame temperature in combustion zone, effectively suppressing thermal
nox and block nox. And the abrasion effect is reduced, it can reduce nox by
50% substantially, lowering treatment load and operating costs of downstream
denitrification facilities such as SCR activity. These are the two mainstream
stream flame patterns for low nitrogen combustion.
The left is four-corner tangential finding.
The right is front and rear wall opposed finding.
For the left method, it's mainly used for the low volatile
and the low heating value code.
And for the front and rear finding,
it's mainly for the high volatile and high heating
Next technology is circulating fluidized bag or CRP technology.
Its core principle lies in its unique circulating combustion method.
It has a closed-loop system of combustion separation reflux recombustion,
which greatly improves combustion efficiency and fuel adaptability.
This kind of combustion method brings four core advantages.
First is wide field adaptability, compatible with multiple field types.
Second is stable operation with wide load, adapting to great peak shearing,
because for CERB, its load regulation can be very wide, so it's adapting to great peak shearing.
The third is integration in furnace, including desilverization, low cost, and high efficiency.
The fourth is low temperature combustion inhibition.
Because for semi-boiler, its combustion temperature is relatively low compared to the polarized coal boiler.
So its thermal NOx concentration is low.
So it has no NOx original emission.
OK.
This is the boiler principle and structure.
Fuel and limestone is injected into the boiler furnace.
In the boiler furnace, they are fluidized by the primary air
from the draft fan.
And in the furnace, the coal, the fuel, is combusted completely, and the ash is separated
by the separator, the ash is separated by the separator and returned back to the furnace.
because in the boiler it has a large amount of bad material and the material has a large amount of heat.
So, the self-border is suitable for low heating value of silver and low, high silver, is suitable
for low heating value of coal and high silver coal.
For self-border, it can even combust some, such as the solid waste, municipal, municipal
solid waste. And this is the CFB boiler and the PowerWise Coat boiler from Paris. You
can see from this table, although the PowerWise Coat has a higher thermal efficiency, its thermal
efficiency is greater than 99%. And for the thermal efficiency, the combustion efficiency
efficiency is greater than 99%, and for the thermal efficiency, or power efficiency, for
neutral supercritical unit, it can be greater than 48%, but for CM baller, its conduction
efficiency is 98%, a little small, a little low than the polarized core, and its power
Power efficiency can reach 45%, also a little lower than the power-wise code.
But for power-wise code, it usually combusts the high-quality code, but for CFE power,
it combusts the low-quality or low-heating value code.
And for the coal consumption, because for coal consumption, it's related to the power
efficiency.
efficiency. So, for the parallelized coal, it's thermal efficiency, power efficiency
is high, so its coal consumption is low. It's about 290 grams per kilowatt hour. While for
the CN boiler, its coal consumption is a little higher. It's about 305 grams per kilowatt
And for NOx emission, for power riser coke, its NOx emission is 1,800 to 1,200 mg per
meter cube.
This is the NOx concentration from the boiler after that, not from the power plant emission.
And for self-boiler, because it is low nitrogen combustion, low nitrogen combustion.
So it's not emission and the oil outlet is 200 milligrams per meter cube.
It's high efficiency in thermos.
Desulfurization can reduce tail end facility cost.
It can reduce the cost of desulfurization facility.
So from this table we can find that although polarized coal boilers are more efficient
when burning high quality coal, CFB boilers have obvious advantages in burning low quality
coal.
Pollutant control performance and peak shearing capability over all in specific scenarios
the levelized cost of energy for CFB is more competitive.
And for the load regulation and life cycle cost,
I forgot to say just now.
For the paralyzed coal, its load regulation is usually 50% to 100%,
but for the CFB, its load regulation is 30% to 110%.
which means it has better load regulation and it will be capital for the power grid.
China is a technology leader in the CFB border field with world's largest market share,
especially achieving major breakthroughs in high parameter, high capacity of CFB technologies.
This figure, the right figure is the Pingshuo CFB Power Plant located in Shanxi province, which is the world's first 360 MW CFB unit.
Next core technology is neutral supercritical technology.
Its core principle is to break through efficiency bottlenecks by increasing spin parameters
breaking critical point.
We know for the critical point, its critical pressure is 22 MPa, and its critical temperature
is 374 Celsius degrees.
Both temperature and pressure increases bring efficiency gains, with temperature having
a more significant impact.
This chart, the right chart, shows the trend of efficiency improvement under different
parameters, clearly indicating that higher parameters is the inevitable direction of
technology development.
From the right chart, we can find that when we increase the temperature, this is the misting temperature from 600 degrees,
and this is the reheat temperature, this is the misting temperature.
When we increase the MIS-D temperature from 600 degrees to 700 degrees, the power efficiency
can reach about 5 to 6 percent, 5 to 6 percent.
That's why for the neutral supercritical power plant, we will develop 700 temperature MIS-D,
we call it 700 plan in China, 700 plan in China.
Then we increase the pressure, the misting pressure, the horizontal axis is the misting
pressure.
When we increase the misting pressure, the power efficiency also increases, but it increases
It's a little small, it's a little small,
not like the temperature, it is very obvious.
OK, compared to conventional supercritical unit,
usual supercritical unit has higher spin pressure
and spin temperature.
For conventional supercritical unit,
its min-spin pressure is between 23 to 27 nanopascal.
And mainstream temperature is between 540 to 560,000 degrees.
But for neutral supercritical unit,
its mainstream pressure is greater than 27 nanopascal.
And its mainstream temperature is between 508 to 600 degrees.
And for conventional supercritical,
its power efficiency is about 2% higher than sub-critical unit.
And co-consumption is between 290 to 300 grams per pound.
However, for neutral supercritical unit,
its power efficiency is about 5% higher than sub-critical unit.
and coal consumption is between 270 to 280 grams per kilowatt-hour.
Neutral supercritical technology is currently the most efficient
clean coal power generation technology.
China has the world's largest application scale in this field
and continues to lead in technology.
By the end of 2024, installed capacity of USC units exceeded 320 GW, accounting for nearly 60% of the total qualified programs in China.
In Lisbon, the world's first 630 Celsius degree double reheat USC million kilowatt units was put into operation.
With power generation efficiency exceeding 50% for the first time, it is setting a new world record.
Next technology is deep peaking technology.
technology. Peak-sheathing technology is through the technical retrofits. The minimum operating
load limit of generating units can be overcome. Units can maintain stable combustion and safe
operating under operation conditions of 20% to 50% rated power. Efficiency, including
cooling unit flexibility and peak shearing capacity.
Comprehensive retrofits of boiler, steam turbine,
thermal power decoupling system, and control system,
units can operate stable at lower loads.
This enables them to better accommodate power grid
fluctuations and create room for the integration
of new engines such as wind and solar power.
By the end of 2024,
China has completed flexibility
retrofits for coal-fired generating units with a
total capacity of 210 GW,
which has greatly enhanced the power system's peak-sheeting
capacity. For policy orientation,
implementation, implement the requirement of retrofit all eligible units, promote co-fired
power from mains power source to regulating power source, and support achievement of dual
carbon goals.
Okay, next, we enter chapter three, where I will introduce several advanced technologies
for clean coal power generation, including neutral low-emission technologies, CC-UTAS technology, ORC technology,
coal power integrated with renewable energy technology.
The first advanced technology is flue gas neutral low-emission technology, which has been widely popularized in China.
It's not a single technology, but a set of combined processes, from low nitrogen combustion
inside boilers, to SCR denitrification, to high efficiency dust removal technology, to
to wet food gas desuponization.
And finally, is the wet electrostatic precipitator.
And by this series of methods,
completely pollutant control chip is formed
to ensure emission on the strict pollutant standard.
And the effect of neutral low emission transformation
This table shows the Bruton standard in 2004 and 2012.
This is the 2004 standard, and this is the 2012 standard.
This is the newest emissions standard in China now.
It's still in effect.
Okay, you can see the change of dust, sulfur, it should be sulfur oxide, nitric oxide.
For 2004 standard, its dust limitation is 50 mg per m3 for the new power plant.
And this is for the old power plant, it's 200.
And for silver oxides, its emission is 400 mg per m3 for the new power plant,
500 for old power plant.
NOx is 450 for new power plant and 1100 for the old power plant.
Well, for the 212 standard, you can find the emission limitation has been decreased greatly,
decreased, decreased greatly, which means it has a very strict standard.
For the dust, its limitation is 20, 20 milligrams per meter cube for the key regions,
such as Peking, Shanghai, Hebei province.
and 30 for other regions, and for NOx, sulfur oxides is 50 for key regions and 200 for other regions.
For NOx, it's 100 for key regions and 200 for other regions.
And for the investment cost, the neutral low emission retrofit for a single 300 megawatt
unit cost about 150 to 250 million CNY, Chinese money, CNY.
And for the life cycle cost, inside SCR catalyst replacement,
de-supervisor consumption, and station service power.
For economic and social benefits, intelligent virtual seating can reduce environmental chemical consumption by 8 to 15%.
Chinese government has issued dual carbon goals, carbon peaking and carbon neutrality.
Carbon peaking before 2030 and carbon neutrality in 60.
The roadmap is divided into three stages.
First, from 2021 to 2030, we achieve carbon peaking.
31 to 45, rapid reduced carbon emissions.
46 to 60, deep decarbonization and carbon neutrality.
And the key measures to achieve the dual carbon goals include clean and efficient utilization of coal in the power industry,
industry, develop new and renewable energy sources, carbon reduction retrofits in key
industries and fields, and last is carbon capture utilization and storage technology
or CCUS technology. CCUS technology is a key technology on the path to achieve dual carbon
It mainly has three parts.
The first is post-combustion capture.
This capacity is the most major.
It directly separates carbon dioxide from the flue gas
with a simple process and easy transformation of achieved plans.
The second is pre-combustion capture.
First, gasified fuels provide thin gas, then generate high concentration carbon oxides.
Its concentration is 30 to 60 percent, and hydrogen, reducing carbon dioxide separation
energy consumption, such as the ITCC technology, belong to this method, belong to the O-ray
And this method has higher capture efficiency, but it also has disadvantages, its investment
cost is very huge.
Last is oxygen-fueled combustion.
It uses pure oxygen-fueled combustion, low gas is made of carbon dioxide and vapor, yielding
high concentration carbon dioxide after condensation.
This method also has the disadvantage of huge investment costs.
Each part has its own advantages and disadvantages and needs to be selected according to specific conditions.
And this diagram shows the four technical frameworks of CC-wise, including carbon dioxide
source, capture, storage, utilization, and composition.
First, carbon dioxide is produced from various emission sources, such as power plants, such
as the nature, such as air, such as from the vehicle.
Then, carbon dioxide is captured and separated by multi-technologies such as the chemical
absorption, physical absorption, absorption method, waste, biological method.
After capture, carbon dioxide has two major directions, geological storage or further
After capture, the carbon dioxide concentration is increased by two methods.
First is storage, storage in the geologic deep sea or sea-line layer.
Next is physical utilization and conversion, such as chemical conversion.
For these two methods, we can use carbon dioxide for some products, such as fuels, chemicals, and carbonates.
Neutral emission technologies and CCUS technologies are key to achieving near zero emissions from coal power.
By the end of 2024, over 1,050 GW of coal-fired power units in China have been retrofitted, accounting for over 94% in service units.
And the right figure is the Chinese Zhening Power Plant.
This power plant is located in Shaanxi province.
This project has been towards largest qualified power carbon capture project
with an annual capture capacity of 1.5 million tons, but the high cost remains the main challenge
for its promotion.
4RC technology, shock for organic rankine cycle technology, is a waste heat recovery
It uses special organic working fluids to convert medium and low temperature waste such
as exhaust gas from power plants and heat from circulating water.
It has a simple system and the technology is safe and reliable.
It is a power tool to improve energy utilization efficiency.
Its core technical advantages include low temperature adaptability, high energy utilization efficiency,
it can effectively utilize locally-based heat resources, and greatly improving the compressive energy recovery rate.
And this table compares the OIC technology with traditional steam cycle technology.
Traditional steam cycle technology such as the power plant technology is traditional steam technology.
From this table we can see for the steam cycle,
for steam cycle is habitable heat source is high temperature source is usually greater than 400
degree and for organic cycle is heat source is low or medium temperature source its temperature is
between 90 degree to 400 degree so it had a wide range heat source and the system has characteristics
For steam cycle, it is high pressure. It has large air occupied.
And for the organic cycle, it is low pressure and it's compact and it's modular.
And for the resource consumption, for steam cycle, it must use the water.
So it must have water supply because there is high water consumption.
And for the organic cycle, there is no water consumption.
So it can use air-cooling.
So for the organic cycle, it can be applied in different scenarios,
such as industrial waste heat recovery for food and security water.
It can be also applied in some marine engineering,
and engineers such as Lin Chang-of for the waste utilization.
The integration of coal power with renewable energy is an important direction for future energy development.
environment. Through various models such as wind-cold storage integration, flexibility
retrofitting, multi-energy integration, and green hydrogen covering, coal power can better
play its regulatory role and help build a more stable and low-carbon new power system.
This project, the LIFE project, is the peaking shearing coal-fired power supporting the large-scale new energy in the Badan desert located in Shanxi province in western China.
It contains four 1,000 MW high-efficiency neutral supercritical coal-fired power plants
with deep peak chipping capability to accommodate local wind energy and solar energy.
And this diagram shows a typical integrated energy system, including PV, wind power, fuel cells, and gas boilers as energy resources.
PCS and batteries realize energy storage while EMS optimizes the whole system,
electric, heating, cooling, gas, and transformation nodes.
For this integrated energy system, it has multiple energy supply.
This is the wind power, this is the solar power, and this is the thermo power boiler.
And it's outlet products, also includes multiple products, includes electricity, heating, cooling,
gas and for the recharge of some vehicles.
Okay, next is the last chapter, conclusion and suggestion.
We will analyze industrial hotspots, costs and policies and put forward strategic outlooks.
For the cost and investment for new built units,
The investment suggestion in neutral civil-grid unions is about 4,000 CNY per kilowatt, with the best economic efficiency.
And for retrofit projects, the flexibility retrofit cost is about 30 to 90 CNY per kilowatt.
The CCPS benefit cost is the highest, highly relevant on policy incentives.
For existing CCT, we adopted monetary standards, financial support, green finance, and market-based mechanisms.
For future improvements, to improve the capacity price mechanism, improve the energy service market, strengthen carbon market incentives.
And for the strategic action guidelines, include deep transformation and upgrading, focus on core technology, promote energy hub transformation,
stimulation, steaming rates, and the generous motivation to strengthen international cooperation.
And the current hot thoughts and outlooks for green coal power technology are mainly reflected in four aspects.
First, the demand for reliability enhancement.
Second, the integration of CCUS technology for deep decarbonization.
Third, the transformation for coal-fired power plants into intelligent energy service.
And finally, including operation efficiency through intelligence and digitalization.
Okay, that's all for my report. Thank you for your attention.
Question?
Yes, Mr. Chairman, we have at least 15 minutes for the Q&A.
please feel free to raise your hand if you have question. Don't be nervous, don't be shy.
I have one. Hello, thank you very much for your presentation. I have a question, it's
a long question so I read it. Given that this new technology reduced the LCOE, do you have
estimations of their impacts on the short-run marginal cost of generation is
there any distinction between technologies that requires significant
capital invest in new infrastructure versus process basis approach and how
does each case translate into chains in the marginal cost of dispatch I met in
in my economy the marginal cost is very important to the merit order so any
affectation in marginal cost impact how works our system that is the core of these these questions
okay sorry your first sentence the first the first again do you have any estimations of
the impact of these new technologies on the short-run marginal cost of generation
generation? This is the first. CMG, the marginal cost. The first one. Do you talk about two
two technologies of course the first one is the cfb cfb yes cfb for the shorter cost
i think for cfb is compared to the power riser code and cfb account accounted for about
about 10% or 20% in China.
And the main thing is the power life code.
For the CFP, I think it's compatible for the low heating
value code.
If you combust a low heating value code,
I think the short cost is very obvious.
But if you use the PowerLight Coal boiler to combust the low heating value coal or high
sewer coal, the short cost is not good.
But for how many years you can require the investment cost, I have no detailed data.
Don't worry, it's a deep question, so no problem.
Yes, it's a deep question. It's needed for the LCOE calculation, including the investment, including the fuel, including the operation cost.
Okay, I am perfect with that. Thank you very much.
In Russia, the average age of thermal power plants is more than 40 years, and we have
a program called modernization of thermal power plant capacity, and the question is
shows the variations of ultra-low-emission retrofits for a single 600 MW plant.
It's about 150-250 million U.S.
And the question is, are these estimates relevant both for coal and gas power plants?
It's an awful coal power plant, because in China, the gas power plant, its share is small.
Although in recent years, for pollution, for the environment protection,
protection, we developed a gas power plant, especially in certain vacuum areas, to reduce
the pollutant emissions, but its share is still very small because the total capacity
is very, very large. So although we developed it in recent 10 years for gas power, it's
For the coal power, in binary, its operation cost is the lowest, while gas power is a little
a little lower than the coal power is about 0.5 to 0.1 CMY for 1 kW.
And the second question is, if it's relevant for coal power plant,
The level of decreasing of pollution is the same if the modernized power plants continue working not in peaking regime but in phase mode regime.
So after modernized unit continue working in phase regime.
Even in this situation, the level of pollution decreased after the materialization,
or no, these estimations are relevant only in the regime.
So we need to modernize the unit and switch to a different regime after the materialization.
You mean for the low-skilled partner?
I mean for the low-skilled partner.
Yes, that is correct. Not for the market.
So here they do it, which is a working basis.
Yes, yes, yes, because there is a basis.
And ultimately the issue is that they need
The level of pollution, of the sanitation, decreased quite a bit, quite a bit.
I think the impact should be more in the new sector,
taking advantage of an associated infrastructure, this technology for the environment.
20-well standard and 20-0-4 standard.
The difference is about five times.
So, and this difference connected only with the ecological aspects
or both with the regime of using this power plant.
So, switching point.
Yes, in one slide, it's right there.
The table compared the two standards, two emissions standards, 2001 and 2014.
There is some data about the new-build parkland and the old.
For the old power plant, the method to decrease the pollutant emission is very tricky,
such as deserialization and electrification technologies to make its pollutant emission lower.
However, its emission is still higher than the new-built power plant.
That's why the standard you can find for new-built power plant, it has stricter standards limitation.
But for the old power plant, even for retrofitting, it has higher limitation.
And for China, for China, for the new built coal-fired power plant, we have applied one
policy, it's called, in Chinese it's called shangda yaxi, in English it's not, it's meaningless
is to rebuild large-scale power plant, but we limit the small-scale power plant. The
small-scale power plant is gradually stopped. And the new-build power plant now, there are
are only two scales, one is 1000 megawatt, another is 600 megawatt, and 660 megawatt
belong to the 600 megawatt level. And then the other scale, such as 300 megawatt, and
and the mass scale is stopped gradually.
On the new build, there is no small scale, small scale.
Okay, so maybe there is some combined heat and power,
combined heat and power power plant.
It has the scale of 300 megawatt,
but that's the minimum scale.
So the new-built power plant, they all use the new standard, so it has stricter implementation.
Thank you. I talked about the old power plants, which need to be retrofitted to increase the ecological standard.
So the average, if we talk about, for example, a thermal power plant, which is working in combined cycle, heat and power, we can use the evaluation about 2 million UAS, less than 500 megawatts of power, to increase the ecological standard and decrease the pollutions five times.
If you use combined data and power, it's going to be better.
This is Moises Inda from Mexico.
Thank you for your presentation.
So you mentioned about the CO2 storage by CCUS Technologies.
So I wanted to ask you, is this something that can be in any country,
in any economy, or water domain concerns, so on,
non-geological regulatory concerns that we have to look after in order to implement this?
The CCUS has CO2 storage, CCUS that you mentioned. Is this something that can be implemented
in any economy, in any country, or we have to look after specific conditions in order to...
I have no detailed data because CCUS technology is working technology.
technology design, new technology.
And in China, actually speaking, in China,
the CCUS technology is mainly a demonstration project,
demonstration project.
Such as the case I mentioned in my slide, in my presentation,
The Zhengning power plant in Shaanxi province can capture and treat 1.5 million tons of dioxide.
But it's a demonstration, still a demonstration, it's a benchmark for all the power plants.
Because for CCUS, it has a very higher cost. If we use CCUS per kilowatt hour, power will increase about 0.1 to 0.2, same line.
So its proportion, its share is still low in China, lower than, it's less than 1%.
So for us economists, I don't have data. I think maybe it's developing. We are doing that. Thank you.
Hello. You've mentioned in your presentation that around 90% of your coal capacity, I think it's 1,050 gigawatts of capacity, has been retrofitted.
Okay, so that's 90%. So what happened to the 6%? Did you retire coal plants? Or did you repower or retrofit to gas?
Because 94% of your capacity is already retrofitted, you reported in your presentation. So I just want to know what happened to the 6%?
94% is retrofitted, I mentioned in the last several slides.
This retrofit is not all CCUS retrofit.
It's retrofit means low emission retrofits.
They focus on very low emission of silver oxides,
nitrogen oxides, and especially dust, especially dust.
For 15 years, or 20 years, we hold the IPEC conference in Beijing
to discuss the climate, the environment.
And during that period, the dust, the very small dust emission is very high, so the weather
is not very good.
So after that, they focus on the dust removal, especially dust removal.
And for power plant, they use not only the electrostatic dust removal technology, they
We also use the bag filter technology to remove the dust to the very, very strict limitation,
very, very strict standard.
So here, in this 94% benefit, it mainly refers to the dust, socks limitation, and for very
Very few power plant demonstration projects use CCUS, because CCUS is a developing technology,
we are still developing knowledge and making it more and more advanced.
But for the large scale of the CCUS in China, we have no conditions.
Thank you, thank you very much.